Francisco Martínez. Technical Writer

Senior Technical Writer with over 23 years of experience and more than 16 years in writing and developing technical publications. Seeking work opportunities to further enhance my skills as a Technical Writer.

I'm also open to freelance writing and editing work.

✓ Accomplishments❖ Efficiency☒ Goals☒ End result of docs

Contact

@ Send a mail

in LinkedIn

G GitHub

y Twitter

Experience

Tech Mahindra TECHNICAL WRITER

Airbus L&M Programs Maintenance Docs TID Support

ijuly 2017 - Present | Seville, Spain (Hybrid)

Quest Global TECHNICAL WRITER

Airbus MRTT Catalog & Structure Manual Responsible

in october 2006 - june 2017 | Seville, Spain

Abengoa Senior Project Designer

october 2005 - october 2006 | Seville, Spain

Hidral | Senior Project Designer

iune 2005 - october 2005 | Seville, Spain

Auxiple Outsourcing | Airbus A380 Technical | Illustrator

december 2004 - june 2005 | 🔀 Seville, Spain

Tecnocontrol | Senior Designer

iseptember 2004 - december 2004 | Seville, Spain

Dinotec Industrial Draftsman

ijune 2004 - september 2004 | Seville, Spain

Nilo - Aqualia | Industrial Draftsman

in october 2000 - june 2004 | Seville, Spain

Education

FPII Industrial Design (Higher National Diploma)

Polytechnic Institute of Seville

iseptember 1998 - june 2001 | Seville, Spain

Languages

English: Full Professional Proficiency (B2)

Spanish: Fluent (Native)

Courses

IT Courses:

30% Confluence Fundamentals. Attlasian Certification.

50% JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures.

freeCodeCamp Certification.

70% Scientific Computing with Python. freeCodeCamp Certification.

100% Responsive Web Design (HTML, CCS).

freeCodeCamp Certification.

100% Automation Engineer Certification: Maven-

Jenkins-Selenium.TM Certificate.

100% Agile: Scrum Management. TM Certificate.

100% VBA and VBScript. TM Certificate.

TW and Design Courses:

100% Aircraft Systems Course: Electrical and Avionics.

100% Introduction to Aeronautical Systems: Hydraulic

and Pneumatic.

100% CAD Specialist.

100% Mechanical Design with CATIA V5.

100% Office Business Management (MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint).

Languages Courses:

100% English Course Upper Intermediate (B2) Semi-Intensive.

100% English Course Intermediate (B1-B2).

100% English Pre-Intermediate level (A2).

100% Simplified Technical English (ASD-STE100 v4).

Markup Languages	TW Tools	lechnical Writing
XML	Arbortex	Wrinting
90%	90%	90%
HTML	Oxigen XML Editor	Translation
80%	50%	70%
CSS	MKDocs	Al tools
70%	80%	60%
Markdown	ULM Lucidchart	SEO
95%	50%	60%
reStructuredText	GitHub	
75%	40%	Specs
	Confluence	S1000D
Code	30%	90%
Python	Airbus DMS IETM CRM	DITA
60%	95%	60%
Javascript		Microsoft Writing Style Guide
45%	App & CMS	60%
SQL	MS Office & G Docs	ASD-STE100
30%	80%	85%
JSON	Adobe	
60%	65%	Spoken languages
VB Script	Wordpress	Spanish
75%	75%	100%
Selenium IDE	Sensei LMS	English
45%	45%	70%

Relevant Skills and Achievements

- Research skills, audience analysis and quality assurance.
- $\begin{tabular}{l} \blacksquare & Documentation \ end-user \ oriented \ and \ visual \ communication. \end{tabular}$
- $\begin{tabular}{l} \begin{tabular}{l} \begin{tabu$
- ☑ Increased end-user satisfaction and received excellent feedback for complex documentation.
- Writing documentation on thousands of topics, such as troubleshooting, standard procedures and functional specifications.